Pearl Jam Twenty is a documentary, music film directed by Cameron Crowe.
Carved from over 1,200 hours of footage spanning the band’s career,
Pearl Jam: Twenty is the definitive portrait of Pearl Jam.
Part concert film, part intimate insider-hang, and
part testimonial to the power of music.
Himself, played by Eddie Vedder.
Himself, played by Stone Gossard.
Himself, played by Jeff Ament.
Himself, played by Mike McCready.
Himself, played by Matt Cameron.
Himself, played by Chris Cornell.
Pearl Jam Twenty (also known as PJ20) is a 2011 American documentary
directed by Cameron Crowe about the band Pearl Jam.
Preliminary footage was being shot as of June 2010.
Crowe completed filming in April 2011, after using 12,000
hours of footage of the band for the documentary.
The film premiered at the 2011 Toronto International Film Festival
and also had an accompanying book and soundtrack.
The documentary charts the history of the band, from the demise of Mother Love Bone, their
battle against Ticketmaster and the tragedy of the Roskilde Festival in 2000.
The film was presented theatrically at select cinemas in the US during the month of
September 2011, and premiered on October 21, 2011, on PBS' American Masters.
It was released on DVD and Blu-ray on October 24, 2011.
A book, written by Jonathan Cohen, was published
concurrent to the film's release.
The film explores themes of musician, rock star,
seattle, washington, grunge, rocker.